<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome! on Nikita Gusarov</title>
    <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome! on Nikita Gusarov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nikitagusarov.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bikes in Grenoble</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-09-18-bikes-in-grenoble/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-09-18-bikes-in-grenoble/</guid>
      <description>Lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve taken a break from the technical publications about R and informatics in general. This is mostly because I was distracted by a more immediate problems: the choice of a bike for this academic year. My contract with the Metrovelo, the most popular bike-rental company in Grenoble, has expired around 10-th september, pushing me to reconsider my travel choices.
In Grenoble, as in many other european towns, the transportation choices are more versatile than in Moscow, or any northern cities in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gift ideas for FOSS enthusiasts</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-09-10-wishlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-09-10-wishlist/</guid>
      <description>Personally I have rather mixed feeling towards the wishlists. Even though having a list of gifts is convenient, it somewhat reduces the joy. However, after some recent discussions I&amp;rsquo;ve realised that probably creating some sort of wishlist may be not such a bad idea. But making this &amp;ldquo;wishlist&amp;rdquo; useful for some other people may be an even better idea.
So, what can be interesting for people who adore gadgets and tinkering, preferring at the same time to stick with some Open Source solutions?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guide des outils</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-09-03-git-fr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-09-03-git-fr/</guid>
      <description>Cette publication est orienté vers les étudiants qui vont suivre des cours ou faire de Projets / mener des TER avec moi cette année. Elle vise à proposer un aperçu des outils essentiels pour faciliter et simplifier le travail. Particulièrement :
 Git GitHub/GitLab/BitBucket (ici nous parlerons du GitLab hebergé par GRICAD) LaTeX Markdown RMarkdown  Ce sont des outils principaux pour bien organiser son travail de la recherche et pouvoir l&amp;rsquo;accompagner par des supports numeriques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a website (part 3)</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-31-website-p3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-31-website-p3/</guid>
      <description>In this part, we are finally approaching one of the most important and interesting topics, when creating a website: the deployment process. I do not believe that this will be the end of the sequence about the websites, because there are some more interesting topics. Among them:
 RSS (Really Simple Syndication) configuration Templates Custom layouts Java Script (JS) embedding Synchronisation Migration And many more  But let&amp;rsquo;s leave these topics for later and focus our attention on the deployment procedure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a website (part 2)</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-29-website-p2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-29-website-p2/</guid>
      <description>So, this post continues the sequence about building a website with R software. Today I&amp;rsquo;ll make focus on the building procedure with the help of previously chosen solution: blogdown.
Site generation with blogdown The procedure of building website with blogdown may be divided into several steps:
 Dependencies installation Theme choice and file-structure generation Building website  Installation As it was stated before, the blogdown package uses Hugo backend to build websites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a website (part 1)</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-28-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-28-website/</guid>
      <description>The idea to write this post (or rather a sequence of posts) appeared when I was attempting to deploy this website, mostly because of the difficulties I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered. So, today&amp;rsquo;s question is: how to deploy a simple static website with R?
First of all, we should start with distinguishing two main steps in website production:
 Building website Deploying the results on the web  These two topics may be rather long to explain, that&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;d rather prefer to separate this post into several parts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LaTeX, publications and `tikz`</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-27-latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-27-latex/</guid>
      <description>Today’s’ experience with helping to submit an article for a journal of Taylor &amp;amp; Francis group was educative and energy draining at the same time. Yesterday was quite a long day dedicated to styling the document, while now I had only figures to worry about. Later, I’ll definitely have to write some guide about academic writing and how R software, which can be useful in this aspect. But now lets speak about some useful tips in using tikz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-26-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-26-introduction/</guid>
      <description>My name is Nikita Gusarov and I&amp;rsquo;m currently doing my Doctoral studies at the University Grenoble Alpes located in France.
 My work is primarily focused on exploration of the performances of Discrete Choice Models (DCM) in modelling individual behaviour. This is a rather breathtaking topic, because of its interdisciplinary nature. I have to deal at the same time with different techniques from quite distant fields, among which:
 Statistics Econometrics Machine Learning Combinatorics and Optimisation  As well as various behavioural theories, specific for several domains:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Centres of interest  Behavioural Theories Discrete Choice Modelling (DCM) Preference Studies Econometrics Machine Learning (ML) Numerical Optimisation System Administration Workflow Management   Research Projects Discrete Choice Modelling and Behavioural Sciences
 &amp;ldquo;Comparison of discrete choice model performances in presence of heterogeneous preferences in population&amp;rdquo;, M2, Thesis &amp;ldquo;Study of the factors associated with the frequency of public transport use in Grenoble&amp;rdquo;, M2, Advanced econometrics &amp;ldquo;Identification of the network effects in the Discrete Choice Models&amp;rdquo;, M1, Thesis 2  Microeconomics</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Background</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/background/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/background/</guid>
      <description> table th:first-of-type { width: 25%; } table th:nth-of-type(2) { width: 75%; }   Professional experience  2020 - now Grenoble Applied Economics Lab (GAEL), G-SCOP Laboratory, University Grenoble Alpes (UGA), Grenoble INP Exploration of Discrete choice Models performance metrics 2020 GAEL, Grenoble Informatics Laboratory (LIG), Multidisciplinary Institute in Artificial Intelligence (MIAI), UGA Consumer Choice and Preference Modelling with Discrete Choice Models 2019 GAEL, RESMOB IDEX, UGA Identification of network effects with Discrete Choice Models for individual decision making 2018 Analytics Centre of Russian Federation Government   Studies  2020 - now PhD in Economics at UGA, EDSE, CDD provided by UGA 2018 - 2020 Master in Economics at UGA, FEG, IDEX scholarship 2016 - 2018 Licence in Economics at UGA, FEG, IDEX scholarship 2014 - 2018 Bachelor in Economics at Russian Foreign Trade Academy (RFTA), Russian Federation state scholarship before - 2014 School 179 of Moscow Institute of Open Education, Natural Science profile   Languages  Russian Native speaker French (C1) DALF C1 (2018), DELF B2 (2018) English (C1) CAE C1 (2015), LCCI C1 (2016) Italian (B2) Universita per Stragnieri di Perugia certificate C1 (2017) Spanish (B1) No official grading certificate Latin (A2) No official grading certificate   Informatics  Data Science and Everyday Use R, Python, Julia Econometrics and Data Analysis SAS, Stata, Gretl, Analyzer Data Management SQL Web HTML, CSS Other Sphinx, LaTeX  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>To contact me you may find me in Matrix and VKontakte. Or you may just use the contact form below:
Your Name Email Address An email address is required.  Message   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description> Working papers and Conference proceedings  2020 Nikita Gusarov &amp;amp; Amirreza Talebijamalabad &amp;amp; Iragaël Joly, 2020. &amp;ldquo;Exploration of model performances in the presence of heterogeneous preferences and random effects utilities awareness,&amp;rdquo; Working Papers hal-03019739, HAL.   Thesis &amp;amp; Memoires  2020 Nikita Gusarov, &amp;ldquo;Performance comparison of the discrete choice models of consumer choice&amp;rdquo;, M2 Thesis, FEG, UGA 2019 Nikita Gusarov, &amp;ldquo;Analyse de la participation au marché du travail et des déterminants du salaire : Application d’un modèle de sélection endogène et essais d’utilisation des techniques en grande dimension&amp;rdquo;, M1 Memoire (in french), FEG, UGA 2018 Nikita Gusarov, &amp;ldquo;Построение модели прогнозирования валютных курсов с целью оценки их влияния на внешнюю торговлю России со странами ЕС&amp;rdquo;, Bachelor Y4 Thesis (in russian), Faculty of International Trade, RFTA   Other works  2020 Nikita Gusarov, Tom Viellescazes, &amp;ldquo;Etude des facteurs associés à l’usage fréquent des transports en commun urbain&amp;rdquo; 2019 Arnaud Blanc, Nikita Gusarov and Sasha Picon &amp;ldquo;Etude des effets des pesticides sur le marché des vins de table&amp;rdquo;  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
