<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Nikita Gusarov</title>
    <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Nikita Gusarov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OnlyKey for Linux login</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2022-01-29-onlykey-for-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2022-01-29-onlykey-for-linux/</guid>
      <description>After receiving a hardware authentication token for the New Year, I&amp;rsquo;ve spent quite a lot of time on the configuration. Even though I&amp;rsquo;d already modified my security model by the end of 2021, I needed to reconsider it once again. Now my password management framework comprises three elements:
 Hardware security token (OnlyKey) for most sensitive credentials and 2FA (two facto authentication like OTP, FIDO2 / U2F) Self-hosted cloud storage (Vaultwarden) for less sensitive credential Encrypted password database (Pass-Tomb) on a USB  Each of these elements requires a separate post, but for now I&amp;rsquo;ll focus only on the first part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog revival</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-12-27-blog-revival/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-12-27-blog-revival/</guid>
      <description>After some difficult time without much ideas about how to write, and what to write about, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to review this blog. Many things have happened since I&amp;rsquo;ve last time update this page: new Machine Learning courses, participation in the AIMS2 program preparation, first time teaching of the M2 Econometrics course and many more. In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll attempt to describe some of my new ideas concerning this blog&amp;rsquo;s past and future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RStudio or VS Code</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-12-27-rstudio-or-vs-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-12-27-rstudio-or-vs-code/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s highly probable, that the days to come will be marked with a lot of activity on this blog. Some of the last discussions pushed me forward to start publishing on several topics I&amp;rsquo;ve considered as not worth of it. Among the most interesting points comes the discussion of the R related ecosystem. This topic regroups both the discussion about the FOS Software, as well as the R language itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shortcuts in Vim style</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-09-26-shortcuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-09-26-shortcuts/</guid>
      <description>Some while ago I had an interesting discussion concerning the different approaches to workflow organisation and learning. It happened around at the same time, that I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered the Vimium browser extension. This coincidence lead me to write this blog-post about the workflow organisation and usage of shortcuts in everyday life. To keep the content simple, I&amp;rsquo;ll start with some general ideas on using shortcuts and then present some advantages of using their Vim-style version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bikes in Grenoble</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-09-18-bikes-in-grenoble/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-09-18-bikes-in-grenoble/</guid>
      <description>Lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve taken a break from the technical publications about R and informatics in general. This is mostly because I was distracted by a more immediate problems: the choice of a bike for this academic year. My contract with the Metrovelo, the most popular bike-rental company in Grenoble, has expired around 10-th september, pushing me to reconsider my travel choices.
In Grenoble, as in many other european towns, the transportation choices are more versatile than in Moscow, or any northern cities in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gift ideas for FOSS enthusiasts</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-09-10-wishlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-09-10-wishlist/</guid>
      <description>Personally I have rather mixed feeling towards the wishlists. Even though having a list of gifts is convenient, it somewhat reduces the joy. However, after some recent discussions I&amp;rsquo;ve realised that probably creating some sort of wishlist may be not such a bad idea. But making this &amp;ldquo;wishlist&amp;rdquo; useful for some other people may be an even better idea.
So, what can be interesting for people who adore gadgets and tinkering, preferring at the same time to stick with some Open Source solutions?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guide des outils</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-09-03-git-fr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-09-03-git-fr/</guid>
      <description>Cette publication est orienté vers les étudiants qui vont suivre des cours ou faire de Projets / mener des TER avec moi cette année. Elle vise à proposer un aperçu des outils essentiels pour faciliter et simplifier le travail. Particulièrement :
 Git GitHub/GitLab/BitBucket (ici nous parlerons du GitLab hebergé par GRICAD) LaTeX Markdown RMarkdown  Ce sont des outils principaux pour bien organiser son travail de la recherche et pouvoir l&amp;rsquo;accompagner par des supports numeriques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a website (part 3)</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-31-website-p3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-31-website-p3/</guid>
      <description>In this part, we are finally approaching one of the most important and interesting topics, when creating a website: the deployment process. I do not believe that this will be the end of the sequence about the websites, because there are some more interesting topics. Among them:
 RSS (Really Simple Syndication) configuration Templates Custom layouts Java Script (JS) embedding Synchronisation Migration And many more  But let&amp;rsquo;s leave these topics for later and focus our attention on the deployment procedure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a website (part 2)</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-29-website-p2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-29-website-p2/</guid>
      <description>So, this post continues the sequence about building a website with R software. Today I&amp;rsquo;ll make focus on the building procedure with the help of previously chosen solution: blogdown.
Site generation with blogdown The procedure of building website with blogdown may be divided into several steps:
 Dependencies installation Theme choice and file-structure generation Building website  Installation As it was stated before, the blogdown package uses Hugo backend to build websites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a website (part 1)</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-28-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-28-website/</guid>
      <description>The idea to write this post (or rather a sequence of posts) appeared when I was attempting to deploy this website, mostly because of the difficulties I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered. So, today&amp;rsquo;s question is: how to deploy a simple static website with R?
First of all, we should start with distinguishing two main steps in website production:
 Building website Deploying the results on the web  These two topics may be rather long to explain, that&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;d rather prefer to separate this post into several parts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LaTeX, publications and `tikz`</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-27-latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-27-latex/</guid>
      <description>Today’s’ experience with helping to submit an article for a journal of Taylor &amp;amp; Francis group was educative and energy draining at the same time. Yesterday was quite a long day dedicated to styling the document, while now I had only figures to worry about. Later, I’ll definitely have to write some guide about academic writing and how R software, which can be useful in this aspect. But now lets speak about some useful tips in using tikz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-26-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-26-introduction/</guid>
      <description>My name is Nikita Gusarov and I&amp;rsquo;m currently doing my Doctoral studies at the University Grenoble Alpes located in France.
 My work is primarily focused on exploration of the performances of Discrete Choice Models (DCM) in modelling individual behaviour. This is a rather breathtaking topic, because of its interdisciplinary nature. I have to deal at the same time with different techniques from quite distant fields, among which:
 Statistics Econometrics Machine Learning Combinatorics and Optimisation  As well as various behavioural theories, specific for several domains:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
