<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Nikita Gusarov</title>
    <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Nikita Gusarov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building a website (part 2)</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-29-website-p2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-29-website-p2/</guid>
      <description>So, this post continues the sequence about building a website with R software. Today I&amp;rsquo;ll make focus on the building procedure with the help of previously chosen solution: blogdown.
Site generation with blogdown The procedure of building website with blogdown may be divided into several steps:
 Dependencies installation Theme choice and file-structure generation Building website  Installation As it was stated before, the blogdown package uses Hugo backend to build websites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a website (part 1)</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-28-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-28-website/</guid>
      <description>The idea to write this post (or rather a sequence of posts) appeared when I was attempting to deploy this website, mostly because of the difficulties I’ve encountered. So, today’s question is: how to deploy a simple static website with R?
First of all, we should start with distinguishing two main steps in website production:
Building website Deploying the results on the web  These two topics may be rather long to explain, that’s why I’d rather prefer to separate this post into several parts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LaTeX, publications and `tikz`</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-27-latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-27-latex/</guid>
      <description>Today’s’ experience with helping to submit an article for a journal of Taylor &amp;amp; Francis group was educative and energy draining at the same time. Yesterday was quite a long day dedicated to styling the document, while now I had only figures to worry about. Later, I’ll definitely have to write some guide about academic writing and how R software, which can be useful in this aspect. But now lets speak about some useful tips in using tikz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-26-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-26-introduction/</guid>
      <description>My name is Nikita Gusarov and I&amp;rsquo;m currently doing my Doctoral studies at the University Grenoble Alpes located in France.
 My work is primarily focused on exploration of the performances of Discrete Choice Models (DCM) in modelling individual behaviour. This is a rather breathtaking topic, because of its interdisciplinary nature. I have to deal at the same time with different techniques from quite distant fields, among which:
 Statistics Econometrics Machine Learning Combinatorics and Optimisation  As well as various behavioural theories, specific for several domains:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
