<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on Nikita Gusarov</title>
    <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on Nikita Gusarov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nikitagusarov.github.io/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-hosting</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2022-02-01-self-hosting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2022-02-01-self-hosting/</guid>
      <description>Today we are going to speak about the self-hosting. Since the start of January I&amp;rsquo;ve spent some time on configuration of my home server for my personal applications. The idea behind this transition was to put some more distance between myself and my dependence on the external services, where I&amp;rsquo;ve no means to control my personal data. The last year, I&amp;rsquo;ve already performed the transition from using the Google Drive and Dropbox to the usage of more private NextCloud solutions (offered by my university,as well as a privacy respecting server in Zurich).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OnlyKey for Linux login</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2022-01-29-onlykey-for-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2022-01-29-onlykey-for-linux/</guid>
      <description>After receiving a hardware authentication token for the New Year, I&amp;rsquo;ve spent quite a lot of time on the configuration. Even though I&amp;rsquo;d already modified my security model by the end of 2021, I needed to reconsider it once again. Now my password management framework comprises three elements:
 Hardware security token (OnlyKey) for most sensitive credentials and 2FA (two facto authentication like OTP, FIDO2 / U2F) Self-hosted cloud storage (Vaultwarden) for less sensitive credential Encrypted password database (Pass-Tomb) on a USB  Each of these elements requires a separate post, but for now I&amp;rsquo;ll focus only on the first part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RStudio or VS Code</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-12-27-rstudio-or-vs-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-12-27-rstudio-or-vs-code/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s highly probable, that the days to come will be marked with a lot of activity on this blog. Some of the last discussions pushed me forward to start publishing on several topics I&amp;rsquo;ve considered as not worth of it. Among the most interesting points comes the discussion of the R related ecosystem. This topic regroups both the discussion about the FOS Software, as well as the R language itself.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
