<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Nikita Gusarov</title>
    <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Nikita Gusarov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nikitagusarov.github.io/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bibliometrix</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2022-02-04-bibliometrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2022-02-04-bibliometrix/</guid>
      <description>Since the start of my Doctoral studies I’ve always performed the literature exploration “the hard way”. Meaning, that I’ve performed most of my literature searches by hand, attempting to manually locate the key articles in the domain. While I’ve got an in-depth comprehension of the field, it remains possible that I’ve overlooked some of interesting literature clusters. However, there always existed a possibility to avoid such mistakes: by performing a thorough bibliometrics study instead of the simple literature overview.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RStudio or VS Code</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-12-27-rstudio-or-vs-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-12-27-rstudio-or-vs-code/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s highly probable, that the days to come will be marked with a lot of activity on this blog. Some of the last discussions pushed me forward to start publishing on several topics I&amp;rsquo;ve considered as not worth of it. Among the most interesting points comes the discussion of the R related ecosystem. This topic regroups both the discussion about the FOS Software, as well as the R language itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a website (part 3)</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-31-website-p3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-31-website-p3/</guid>
      <description>In this part, we are finally approaching one of the most important and interesting topics, when creating a website: the deployment process. I do not believe that this will be the end of the sequence about the websites, because there are some more interesting topics. Among them:
 RSS (Really Simple Syndication) configuration Templates Custom layouts Java Script (JS) embedding Synchronisation Migration And many more  But let&amp;rsquo;s leave these topics for later and focus our attention on the deployment procedure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a website (part 2)</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-29-website-p2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-29-website-p2/</guid>
      <description>So, this post continues the sequence about building a website with R software. Today I&amp;rsquo;ll make focus on the building procedure with the help of previously chosen solution: blogdown.
Site generation with blogdown The procedure of building website with blogdown may be divided into several steps:
 Dependencies installation Theme choice and file-structure generation Building website  Installation As it was stated before, the blogdown package uses Hugo backend to build websites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a website (part 1)</title>
      <link>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-28-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikitagusarov.github.io/post/2021-08-28-website/</guid>
      <description>The idea to write this post (or rather a sequence of posts) appeared when I was attempting to deploy this website, mostly because of the difficulties I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered. So, today&amp;rsquo;s question is: how to deploy a simple static website with R?
First of all, we should start with distinguishing two main steps in website production:
 Building website Deploying the results on the web  These two topics may be rather long to explain, that&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;d rather prefer to separate this post into several parts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
